Jack Fischer

💻 Full-Stack Web Developer. 📤 Occasional Adventurer. 革 Big Fan of Garlic Naan.

Address: Remote/Miami Beach, FL | Email: <u>letsbuild@jackbuildstech.com</u>
Personal Site: <u>https://jackbuildstech.com</u> | GitHub: <u>https://github.com/sunspla-sh</u>

Summary

I enjoy growing and scaling web applications with Docker, Kubernetes, CI/CD pipelines, Unit and E2E Testing, RESTful APIs or GraphQL, preferably Node.js or other JavaScript runtimes on the backend, preferably React on the frontend although I'm open to other SPA libraries and frameworks.

Visit my personal site https://jackbuildstech.com for a summary of my projects and experience or watch my video resume: https://youtu.be/ERXwTo-zWig

Experience

Full Stack Web Development Instructor (Contractor)

Ironhack (https://ironhack.com)

Mar 2022 - Jan 2023

- mack (<u>nttps:// normack.com</u>/
 - My former students collectively earn roughly \$800,000-1,000,000 in annual income as junior web developers (or similar tech jobs) with an average salary in the \$50,000-60,000 range (representing a 50-100% increase in annual income for most of them, because they primarily came from a hospitality or retail service background)
 - Taught 4 cohorts of students to use modern, full stack web development technologies such as the following: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Mobile-first (Responsive) Design, Express, Handlebars, Databases (MongoDB), ODMs (Mongoose), Single-page Applications (React), Version Control (Git and Github), Unit Testing (Jest), Deployment, etc.

Founder

Aug 2020 - Feb 2022

Failed Startups

- Rejected from YCombinator (a startup accelerator) with first startup in the geothermal industry. It was capital-intensive and we had no clear path forward (and no cash), so my co-founders returned to their jobs.
- Continued on solo with a second startup scuba diving booking software-as-a-service. I tried to be smarter this time and build something that required no starting investment. I attempted to pre-sell based on UX/UI wireframes before coding it and found some interested users, but failed to get product-market fit before I ran out of savings.

Carnival Cruise Line (https://carnival.com)

- Built various front end sections of the carnival.com site including updated versions of the checkout review page within the booking engine, mobile menu, modals, banners, sliders etc
- A/B tested code and toggled features using Optimizely to verify that newly coded sections of the site increased overall customer conversions/revenue
- Hired and managed 4 employees/subcontractors doing frontend web development, UX/UI design, and data analytics, who were billed under me and worked alongside me at Carnival

Projects (Practice & Personal)

1) JobAppTrack.com (Web Application and Chrome Extension)

(https://github.com/sunspla-sh/simple-job-app-tracker-react)
Technologies Used:

Docker, Vite, React, CSS, JavaScript, Prisma, SQLite, Node.js, Express, Nodemailer, Handlebars, Open Graph Protocol, CRXJS, pnpm, TurboRepo, Socket.io (Websockets), Fly.io

2) GitBoxDraw.com (Web Application)

(https://github.com/sunspla-sh/github-commit-text-generator)

Technologies Used:

Vite, Sass, HTML, JavaScript, Open Graph Protocol, Node.js, Rollup, JavaScript Obfuscator (Rollup Plugin), npm, DigitalOcean

3) IPomg.com (Web Application)

(https://github.com/sunspla-sh/ipomg-static)

Technologies Used:

Vite, TailwindCSS, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, MaxMind GeoLite2 DB, Node.js, Express, npm, DigitalOcean

4) CommandLineCartography (Script)

(https://github.com/sunspla-sh/command-line-cartography-practice)

Technologies Used:

D3, GeoJSON, TopoJSON, pnpm, U.S. Census Bureau Data

5) S Tier Web Dev (Web Dev Tutorials - YouTube Channel)

(https://www.youtube.com/playlist?list=PLgF6apjFR90209B4006e8qpNV7qUC-bUD) Technologies Used:

HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Various Recording and Editing Software (Kdenlive, OBS, GIMP, YoutubeStudio, Podia)

6) NFL Team Data Scraper (Script)

(https://github.com/sunspla-sh/nfl-team-data-scraper)

Technologies Used:

Puppeteer, Node.js, npm

Tech Skills and Theory

Front-End Web Development

TypeScript, JavaScript, Single-page Applications (React), GraphQL, HTML, CSS, SASS, TailwindCSS, Mobile-first (Responsive) Design, D3, Vite, Chrome Extensions (CRXJS), npm, pnpm, Open Graph Protocol, Websockets (Socket.io)

Back-End Web Development

Node.js, Web Application Frameworks and APIs (Express.js, Nest.js), Databases (MongoDB, PostgreSQL, SQLite), ODMs and ORMs (Mongoose, Sequelize, Prisma), GraphQL, Unit Testing (Jest), Puppeteer, Nodemailer, Email Templating (Handlebars), Websockets (Socket.io), MVC architecture, npm, pnpm, GeoJSON, TopoJSON, JSON, XML

DevOps and Tooling

Version Control (Git), CI/CD (TravisCI), Cloud Infrastructure (DigitalOcean, AWS, Fly.io, Heroku), Docker, Kubernetes, Linux, Monorepos, Bundlers and Build Systems (TurboRepo, Rollup), Postman

Other Skills

Languages:

English (Native),

Spanish (CEFR - Level B1 - SIELE - <u>Credential ID li3knEHpdbkjrFuagvJ7RA==</u>),

Russian (CEFR - Level A2)

Video and Image Editing:

Kdenlive (Video Editing), OBS (Video recording and livestreaming) GIMP (Image Editing)

Education

Spanish (CEFR Level B1) - SIELE

Aug 2020 - Nov 2020

I independently studied Spanish in Playa Del Carmen, Mexico to a tested level of CEFR Level B1 - Intermediate through the SIELE exam. CEFR Level B1 is high enough to gain entrance to some universities in Spain for a fully Spanish curriculum (no classes taught in English) such as Universidad Complutense Madrid while others require B2. My Spanish exam credential can be independently verified at the following website - https://siele.org/en/comprobar-certificado - using my credential ID: <a href="li3knEHpdbkjrFuagyJ7RA=="li3knEHpdkkjrFuagyJ7RA=="li3knEHpdkkjrFuagyJ7R

Full Stack Web Development Boot Camp - Ironhack

Jan 2019 - Mar 2019

10-week intensive (400+ hour) web development boot camp which complimented my existing computer science skills from some of my university classes

Russian (CEFR Level A2) - Moscow State University

May 2016 - Aug 2016

I like learning languages. I studied Russian language and culture at Lomonosov Moscow State University during a summer abroad and also visited various cities in Russia.

Liberal Studies, B.A. - Iowa State University

Aug 2014 - Aug 2018

I should have been focused on building technical skills instead of "following my passion" and taking a bunch of random liberal arts classes. Fortunately, younger me decided to fill some elective classes with computer science subjects, which led to my current career.